人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  小舞
翻译 猪猪
翻译 送小孩
翻译 某羽
翻译 尼克白
翻译 泰斯
校对  泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴 imok
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家幸福筒
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
特效/后期 吉吉·波顿
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第二集
艾菊
Tansy!
-艾菊  -艾菊
- Tansy! - Tansy!
艾菊
Tansy!
你在这儿呢
There you are.
我看不到她  拉姆斯
I can't see her, Ramsay.
艾菊
Tansy!
如果你能跑出树林  就算你赢
If you make it out of the woods, you win!
跑啊艾菊  快跑
Run, Tansy, run!
-艾菊  -她在哪儿
- Tansy. - Where is she?
艾菊  艾菊  艾菊
Tansy, Tansy, Tansy!
好姑娘  安静  好姑娘
Good girls. Down, girls.
安静
Down.
干得好  你也是
Well done. You, too.
我只射伤了她
I only wounded her.
你让她摔倒  这就够了
You brought her down. That's what matters.
射得漂亮  是不是  臭佬
A fine shot. Wasn't it, Reek?
射得漂亮  主人
A fine shot, master.
-夫人  -求您了  大人
- My lady. - Please, my lord.
好疼
It hurts.
亲爱的  别哭啊
Oh, sweet. Don't cry.
很快就结束了
It will be over soon.
她总以为自己美
She thinks she's pretty.
让我一箭射穿她那张脸
Let me put one through her face.
总要慰劳一下猎狗啊  亲爱的
We have to reward the hounds, love.
苦差事都是它们做的
They did all the hard work.
为什么  您的吩咐我都照做
Why? I did whatever you asked.
可是你害米兰达嫉妒了
But you made Myranda feel jealous.
-我会嫉妒她  -大人  求求您
- Me jealous of her? - My lord, please.
你也看到了  你的存在给我惹来了一点麻烦
You can see that your presence has become a bit of a problem.
撕了她  撕了她
Rip her! Rip her!
撕了她
Rip her!
这下美不起来了
Not so pretty now.
你的新手  比旧的好看
Your new hand, it's nicer than the old one.
你说是吧  波德
Wouldn't you agree, Pod?
是纯金的吗
Is it solid gold?
精钢镀金  你不吃东西
Gilded steel. You're not eating.
为什么所有人都不吃东西
Why is no one eating?
我老婆日渐消瘦  我哥哥绝食挨饿
My wife wastes away and my brother starves himself.
-我不饿  -你丢了一只手
- I'm not hungry. - You lost a hand,
又没丢了胃
not a stomach.
尝尝野猪肉
Try the boar.
自打野猪帮瑟曦杀了劳勃  她就吃不够
Cersei can't get enough of it since one killed Robert for her.
举杯
A toast.
敬骄傲的兰尼斯特子孙
To the proud Lannister children.
侏儒  残废  还有疯之母
The dwarf, the cripple, and the mother of madness.
我来擦
I'll clean it up.
不必  我来  你下去吧
No, I'll do it. Leave us.
不过是酒而已
It's only wine.
我不能战斗了
I can't fight anymore.
你的左手呢
What about your left?
握得住剑  但我使剑的本能错了位
I can hold a sword, but all my instincts are wrong.
我连自己的屁股都擦不干净
How can I protect the king
还怎么保护国王
when I can hardly wipe my own ass?
你如今是队长  下命令嘛
You're the Lord Commander now. Command.
让别人去打仗
Let others do the fighting.
你上次看父亲用剑是什么时候
When was the last time Father used a sword?
我不是父亲  我是弑君者
I'm not Father. I'm the Kingslayer.
等人们发现我连鸽子都杀不死...
When people find out I can't slay a pigeon...
那就练习  用另一只手战斗
Train, then. Learn to fight with your other hand.
跟谁练  你吗  没有不透风的墙
With whom? You? Men talk.
一旦有人发现我不能战斗  顷刻满城皆知
Soon as someone discovers I can't fight, he'll tell everyone.
你需要一个身手过硬处事谨慎的剑士
You need a proper, discreet swordsman.
说来也巧  我这里刚好有一个
As it happens, I have just the one.
我弟弟说你口风严
My brother tells me you can keep your mouth shut.
佣兵身上难得的品质
Unusual talent for a sellsword.
他告诉我你拉的屎都是金子
He tells me you shit gold
跟你父亲一样
just like your father.
这地方安全吗
Is this place safe?
有个姓雷古德的骑士
There's this knight, Leygood,
盾牌上画着闪电
got thunderbolts on his shield.
我就在这儿干的他老婆
Right here is where I fuck his wife.
那娘们真能叫
She's a screamer, that one.
没人能听见她  就没人能听见我们
If they don't hear her, they won't hear us.
我从前没见过瓦雷利亚钢
I've never seen Valyrian steel before.
真是好东西  可问题是
She's a beauty. The problem is,
如果你用真家伙
if you fight with an edged blade,
我也得用
I'll have to.
我要是用了真家伙
And if I fight with an edged blade,
就没人活着付我钱了
I'll have no one left to pay me.
我九岁过后再没用过钝剑
I haven't used a sparring sword since I was nine.
乘人不备  你真不愧为勇猛的战士
Bold warrior you are, attacking a man when his guard's down.
那才是最佳时机
Best time to attack a man.
小心了
Mind yourself.
要是我右手还在...
If I still had my right hand...
打算再长一只出来吗
Plan on growing it back?
那就来吧
Come on, then.
开门
Open the gates!
骑兵归来
Riders coming in!
照料好马
Let's get these horses seen to!
父亲  欢迎回家
Father. Welcome home.
瓦妲  这是拉姆斯·雪诺  我的私生子
Walda, this is Ramsay Snow, my bastard.
非常荣幸  母亲
A pleasure, Mother.
你好
Hello.
找人给马喂料  饮水  刷毛
See that the horses are fed, watered, and rubbed down.
带瓦妲夫人去她的房间
And take Lady Walda to her chambers.
这边请  夫人
This way, my lady.
你的战利品呢
Where is your prize?
在猎狗群里
With the hounds.
我要看看他
I'll have a look at him.
听说你剁了弑君者一只手
I hear you took a hand from the Kingslayer.
传得真快  他嚎得那叫一个惨
Word travels. How he screamed.
你一定喜欢
You would have loved it.
父亲
Father.
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
调教而已  他学得慢  但好歹有进步
I trained him. He was a slow learner, but he learned.
你剥他皮了
You flayed him.
就剥了一点
Peeled a few bits.
还去掉了些别的
Removed a few others.
这可是巴隆·葛雷乔伊的儿子和继承人
This was Balon Greyjoy's son and heir.
我们剥敌人的皮都有一千年历史了
We've been flaying our enemies for 1,000 years.
我们的家徽就是剥皮人
The flayed man is on our banners.
我的家徽  不是你的
My banners, not yours.
你不姓波顿  你姓雪诺
You're not a Bolton. You're a Snow.
泰温·兰尼斯特许给我北境
Tywin Lannister has given me the North.
但夺取北境这事儿  他一分力气也不会出
But he won't lift a finger to help me take it.
只要铁民还占领着卡林湾
As long as the ironborn hold Moat Cailin,
我们的军队就只能困在颈泽以南
our armies are trapped south of the Neck.
席恩是个有价值的人质  不是你的玩物
Theon was a valuable hostage, not your plaything.
我本打算用他去换卡林湾
I wanted to trade him for Moat Cailin.
我已经问过了
I already asked.
葛雷乔伊大人拒绝了  蛮子毫无...
Lord Greyjoy refused. Savages have no...
你未经我允许就跟巴隆·葛雷乔伊谈判
You sent terms to Balon Greyjoy without my consent?
您让我做恐怖堡的代理公爵
You made me acting Lord of the Dreadfort.
我做了
I acted.
就因为葛雷乔伊家  我回自家领地
I had to smuggle myself into my own lands
还只能偷偷摸摸的
thanks to the Greyjoys.
我需要席恩
I needed Theon.
我要他完完整整的
I needed him whole.
席恩是我们的敌人
Theon was our enemy.
但是臭佬
But Reek,
臭佬决不会背叛我们
Reek will never betray us.
我对你的信任真是过了头
I placed far too much trust in you.
臭佬  你怎么能让我胡子拉碴的见父亲呢
Reek, how could you let me stand before my father unshaven?
-这样不尊重  -对不起  大人
- It's disrespectful. - I'm sorry, my lord.
给他把剃刀
Give him the razor.
反正我不姓波顿  父亲  这又何妨
I'm not a Bolton, father, what does it matter?
来吧  臭佬
Go on, Reek.
给我刮个干干净净
A nice close shave.
臭佬  告诉父亲
Reek, tell father
史塔克家的布兰和瑞肯在哪儿
where are Bran and Rickon Stark?
我不知道  大人
I don't know, my lord.
你杀了他们
You murdered them
还把他们的尸体挂在临冬城上示众
and displayed their corpses at Winterfell.
臭佬
Reek,
史塔克兄弟是你杀的吗
did you murder the Stark boys?
不是  大人
No, my lord.
杀的是两个乡下小子
Just two farm boys.
烧焦了没人认得
And crisped them so no one would know.
是的  大人
Yes, my lord.
史塔克家一直统治北境
The Starks have always ruled the North.
如果布兰和瑞肯还活着
If Bran and Rickon are alive,
而罗柏·史塔克已死
the country will rally to their side
整个北境将会拥他们为首
now that Robb Stark is gone.
你没听错  臭佬
Oh, that's right, Reek.
罗柏·史塔克死了
Robb Stark is dead.
不好意思
Sorry.
我知道你们亲如兄弟
I know he was like a brother to you.
但我父亲把刀插进了他的心脏
But my father put a knife through his heart.
你感觉如何
How do you feel about that?
-可以出发巡猎吗  -随时
- You ready for a hunt? - Always.
找到那俩男孩  给你千亩良田外加一座城堡
Find those boys and I'll give you 1,000 acres and a holdfast.
你的宠物老鼠知不知道
Your pet rat have any thoughts
他们出了临冬城会去哪里
on which way they went after Winterfell?
琼恩·雪诺在黑城堡
Jon Snow is at Castle Black.
谁他妈的是琼恩·雪诺
Who the fuck is Jon Snow?
他们的私生子哥哥
Their bastard brother.
他有可能保护他们
He could be sheltering them.
他也许知道他们在哪儿
He may know where they are.
就算他不知道  他也是半个史塔克
Even if he doesn't, he's half Stark himself.
也是个威胁
Could be a threat.
你想证明自己是波顿家的人吗
You want to prove yourself a Bolton?
调集你所有的人  向卡林湾进发
Gather whatever men you can and ride for Moat Cailin.
带上你养的畜生
Bring this creature of yours.
说不定能派上点用场
Maybe he'll be of some use.
为家族拿下卡林湾
Take the Moat for the family,
为了我们家族
for our family,
我会重新考虑你的地位
and I'll reconsider your position.
瓦里斯大人  与国王共进早餐吗
Lord Varys. Breakfasting with the king?
如此殊荣家宴异邦人怕是不受欢迎
I'm afraid foreigners aren't welcome at such exclusive affairs.
异邦人真好
Oh, to be foreign.
雪伊被发现了
Shae has been noticed.
珊莎的女仆看见你和她在一起
Sansa's maid saw you with her.
她已经告诉了你姐姐
She already told your sister.
你父亲知道也只是迟早的事
It's only a matter of time before your father hears.
我和我夫人的侍女共处一室罪名成立了
So I'm guilty of being seen with my own wife's handmaiden.
若我父亲问你是否有别的情况
My father will ask you if there's anything more
你撒个高明的谎就是了
and you'll tell him some clever lie.
恕难从命
No, I will not.
要是你父亲和姐姐怀疑我撒谎
How long do you imagine your father and sister would let me live
你觉得我还能活多久
if they suspected me of lying?
我可没有家养佣兵保护
I have no pet sellsword to protect me.
也没有武功盖世的哥哥给我报仇
No legendary brother to avenge me.
只有悄悄给我传信的小小鸟儿
Only little birds who whisper in my ear.
别怪我到时候不为你掉眼泪
Forgive me if I don't weep for you.
没人为蜘蛛或妓女掉眼泪
No one weeps for spiders or whores.
我在狭海对岸有朋友可以接应她
I have friends across the sea who could help her.
她不肯走
She won't leave.
我警告过她太多次这里很危险
I've told her this is a dangerous place
她已经不信了
so many times, she no longer believes it.
你父亲放过话
Your father has promised
下次发现有妓女跟你鬼混  就吊死她
to hang the next whore he finds you with.
你父亲哪次威胁不是说到做到
Have you ever known your father to make an idle threat?
谨代表提利尔家族和河湾地的子民
From House Tyrell and the people of the Reach,
陛下  我很荣幸献给您这尊婚杯
Your Grace, it is my honor to present you with this wedding cup.
祝愿您和我的女儿玛格丽
May you and my daughter Margaery
共饮此杯  健康长寿
drink deep and live long.
好杯  大人
A handsome goblet, my lord.
或者我应该叫您岳父大人
Or shall I call you Father?
这是我的荣幸  陛下
I shall be honored, Your Grace.
她就是我跟您提过的那个妓女
She's the whore I told you about.
黑头发的那个
The dark-haired one.
婚礼前派人把她带到首相塔来
Have her brought to the Tower of the Hand before the wedding.
一本书
A book?
《四王志》  大学士喀斯所著的历史
"The Lives of Four Kings." Grand Maester Kaeth's history
记述了少龙主戴伦
of the reigns of Daeron the Young Dragon,
受神祝福的贝勒
Baelor the Blessed,
庸王伊耿和贤王戴伦的事迹
Aegon the Unworthy, and Daeron the Good.
这是每个国王都该读的书
A book every king should read.
既然打了胜仗
Now that the war is won,
我们都该花点时间长长智慧
we should all find time for wisdom.
谢谢你  舅舅
Thank you, Uncle.
君临唯二的瓦雷利亚钢剑之一
One of only two Valyrian steel swords in the capital,
陛下  这是为您新铸的
Your Grace, freshly forged in your honor.
当心  陛下  瓦雷利亚钢锋利无比
Careful, Your Grace. Nothing cuts like Valyrian steel.
都这么说
So they say.
如此宝剑得有个名字
Such a great sword should have a name.
-我该叫她什么呢  -暴风使者
- What shall I call her? - Stormbringer.
-终结者  -寡妇之嚎
- Terminus. - Widow's Wail.
-狼克星  -寡妇之嚎  我喜欢这名字
- Wolfsbane. - Widow's Wail. I like that.
我每次用这柄剑  都会像是
Every time I use it, it'll be like cutting off
又砍了一次奈德·史塔克的头
Ned Stark's head all over again.
别过来
Don't.
你想在桌子上要我
You want me on the desk?
-怎么了  我的雄狮  -别这么叫我
- What's wrong, my lion? - Don't call me that.
那我该叫你什么
What should I call you?
很遗憾  我们的友谊到此为止了
I'm afraid our friendship can't continue.
友谊
Our friendship?
港口那儿有艘驶往潘托斯的船
There's a ship waiting in the harbor bound for Pentos.
什么
What?
当然  你会有自己的舱室
You'll have your own cabin, of course,
在狭海对岸有幢房子  还有仆人
and across the Narrow Sea a house, servants.
这是什么意思
What is this?
我是有妇之夫
I'm a married man.
我妻子受了很多苦  你也清楚
My wife has suffered a great deal, as you well know.
我不想让她再因我而受伤
I don't want her to suffer anymore on my account.
我必须捍卫自己的誓言
I need to uphold my vows.
她不想要你
She doesn't want you.
-我要好好待她  -你不想要她
- I need to do right by her. - You don't want her.
好好待我们的孩子
By our children.
-你怕什么  -我没害怕
- What are you afraid of? - I'm not afraid.
你怕  你怕你父亲和姐姐
You are. You are afraid of your father and your sister.
难道你要一辈子
You're going to run from
-跟他们躲躲藏藏  -我要你走
- them all your life? - I need you to leave.
我不怕他们  我不会跟他们躲躲藏藏
I'm not afraid of them. I'm not going to run from them.
-雪伊  -我们一起对付他们
- Shae. - We will fight them together.
就像你说过的  我是你的  你是我的
It's like you said, I am yours and you are mine.
你是个妓女
You're a whore!
珊莎才有资格怀我的孩子  你没有
Sansa is fit to bear my children and you are not.
我不能跟妓女相爱
I can't be in love with a whore.
我不能和妓女生子
I can't have children with a whore.
你睡过多少男人
How many men have you been with?
五百个  还是五千个
500? 5,000?
你又睡过多少妓女
How many whores have you been with?
我跟她们在一起时很开心
I have enjoyed my time with all of them
我跟你在一起时更是开心
and I have enjoyed my time with you most of all.
但那已经结束了
But now that time is over.
你在潘托斯会过得很舒服
You'll have a comfortable life in Pentos.
波隆会护送你去搭船
Bronn will escort you to your ship.
请聆听我们
Hear us now.
主啊  接受我们献上的信物
Accept these tokens of our faith, my lord,
带领我们走出黑暗
and lead us from the darkness.
陛下  我向来尽忠尽职
Sire, I served you well.
光之王  为我们指明道路
Lord of Light, show us the way...
赛丽丝  你是我妹妹
Selyse, you're my sister!
你是指引我们的群星
Yours are the stars that guide us.
快劝劝他  劝劝他啊
Tell him! Tell him!
光之王  守护我等
Lord of Light, protect us,
长夜黑暗  处处险恶
for the night is dark and full of terrors.
你看到了吗  他们的灵魂
Did you see? Their souls.
那是他们的灵魂
It was their souls.
真主把他们带走了  你看到了吗
Our lord took them. Did you see?
佛罗伦大人是您内兄
Lord Florent was your brother by law.
他是个异教徒
He was an infidel.
他信奉祖祖辈辈
He worshipped the gods of his fathers
一直信奉的诸神
and their fathers before him.
也是您的父辈信奉的诸神
They were the gods of your fathers, too.
我命令他拆掉神像
I ordered him to tear down his idols.
他不服从
He disobeyed.
他为您的复国大业带来了多少船只
How many ships did he bring to your cause?
多少士兵
How many men?
比你带来的多得多
A good deal more than you.
你看到了吗  戴佛斯爵士
Did you see, Ser Davos?
他们和真主在一起了
They're with our lord now.
他们的罪孽已被焚尽  你看到了吗
Their sins all burned away. Did you see?
他们一定很感激  王后陛下
I'm sure they're more than grateful, my queen.
肉馊了
Meat's off.
食物所剩无几
Our larders are almost empty.
那就上鱼  我们在岛上
Serve fish, then. We're on an island.
你讨厌鱼
You hate fish.
我讨厌很多东西  但我照样承受
I hate a good many things, but I suffer them all the same.
风息堡被围时  我饥饿难耐
When Storm's End was under siege and I was starving,
史坦尼斯拿书给我煮汤
Stannis boiled soup for me from books.
装订胶是从马身上提炼的
The binding glue is made from horses.
有天早上  他在海滩上射下了两只海鸥
One morning, he shot two seagulls on the beach.
烤海鸥是我吃过最美味的食物
I've never tasted anything as good as grilled seagull.
-你还记得吗  -我当然记得
- Do you remember? - Of course I remember.
你挨过饿吗  女士
Have you ever known true hunger, my lady?
挨饿是我小时候唯一的记忆
It's all I knew when I was a child.
直到你找到了光之王吗
Until you found the Lord of Light?
直到他找到了我
Until he found me.
我为女儿的灵魂担心
I fear for our daughter's soul.
每个母亲都应为孩子的灵魂担心
Every mother should fear for her child's soul.
-她是个固执的小畜生  -她是个孩子
- She's a stubborn little beast. - She's a child.
你对她了解不多
You barely know her.
你探访时她会笑  你就以为她很贴心
You think she's sweet because she smiles when you visit.
她阴郁  固执  罪孽深重
She's sullen and stubborn and sinful.
不然光之王怎会在她脸上留下烙印
Why else would the Lord of Light have seen fit to mark her face?
她欠抽
She needs the rod.
她是我女儿  你不准打她
She's my daughter. You will not strike her.
谨遵君命
As you command.
也许梅丽珊卓女士可以和她谈谈
Perhaps the Lady Melisandre could speak with her.
进来
Come in.
你睡了吗  公主殿下
Were you sleeping, Princess?
你看海滩上的仪式了吗
Did you watch the ceremony on the beach?
我听到了
I heard it.
你被吓到了吗
And it frightened you?
亚赛尔爵士是我舅舅
Ser Axel was my uncle.
他一向对我很好
He was always kind to me.
他们现在在更好的地方  公主殿下
They're in a better place now, Princess.
烈火焚尽了他们在凡间的罪孽
The fire cleansed them of the sins of the world.
但他们惨叫了
But they screamed.
女人生孩子时也会叫
Women scream when they give birth.
之后她们就满心喜悦
Afterward they are filled with joy.
之后她们不会变成灰烬
Afterward they aren't ash and bone.
你有好多问题不明白  对吧
You have so many questions, don't you?
我小时候也是这样
So did I when I was a child.
那时候我和你很像
I was much like you.
只不过我不是公主
Only I wasn't a princess.
而且你没有这个
And you didn't have this.
没错
No.
但我受过别的罪  好孩子  相信我
But I suffered in other ways, sweet girl, believe me.
你对诸神知道多少
What do you know of the gods?
我读过《七芒星经》
I read "The Seven-Pointed Star."
那是谎言和谣传
Lies and fables.
修士宣扬七神
Septons speak of seven gods.
其实只有两个神
There are but two--
爱与快乐的光之王
a god of light and love and joy
以及恶与恐惧的暗之王
and a god of darkness, evil, and fear.
他们永世对立
Eternally at war.
那么说  没有七层地狱和七重天堂吗
There are no seven heavens and no seven hells?
地狱只有一个  公主殿下
There's only one hell, Princess.
我们正身在其中
The one we live in now.
阿多
Hodor.
你为什么叫醒我
Why did you wake me?
你神游几个小时了
You've been gone for hours.
我太饿了
I was hungry.
我们都很饿
We're all hungry.
我正在吃东西
I was just eating.
那是夏天在进食
Summer was eating.
你的身体不能靠狼吃的东西过活
Your body can't live on the food your wolf consumes.
在夏天体内久留很危险
Spending too much time in Summer's skin is dangerous.
你不是冰原狼  布兰
You're not a direwolf, Bran.
但那一定很刺激
Must be glorious, though.
奔跑  跳跃  捕猎
To run, to leap, to hunt.
拥有完整的身体
To be whole.
我知道那很诱人
I know that's tempting,
但如果你困在夏天体内太久
but if you're trapped in Summer for too long,
你会忘记为人的感受
you'll forget what it was to be human.
你会忘记我们  布兰
You'd forget us, Bran.
你会忘记你的父母
You'd forget your mother and father.
忘记你的兄弟和姐姐们
You'd forget your brothers and sisters.
忘记临冬城
You'd forget Winterfell.
甚至忘记自己
You'd forget you.
失去了你  我们就失去了一切
And if we lose you, we lose everything.
阿多  带我去树边
Hodor, take me to the tree.
来树下
Look for me...
寻找我
...beneath the tree.
他瞧见我们了
He saw us.
北方
North.
我知道我们要去哪儿了
I know where we have to go.
我们在此见证提利尔家族的玛格丽
Let it be known that Margaery of House Tyrell
与兰尼斯特和拜拉席恩家族的乔佛里
and Joffrey of the Houses Lannister and Baratheon
肉体  心灵  魂魄合二为一
are one heart, one flesh, one soul.
任何干涉他们婚姻的人将受到无情的诅咒
Cursed be he who would seek to tear them asunder.
经由这一吻  献出我的爱
With this kiss, I pledge my love.
我们有新王后了
We have a new queen.
总比让你当好
Better her than you.
-太过了  你说呢  -相当合适
- Bit much, wouldn't you say? - It feels proportionate.
-合适什么  -万众期待的奢华
- Proportionate to what? - The expected extravagance.
往这种荒唐事上砸钱的人
People who spend their money on this sort of nonsense
是留不住钱的
tend not to have it for long.
你死前也该学着享受享受
You ought to try enjoying something before you die.
没准会乐在其中
You might find it suits you.
现在没空  梅斯  我跟泰温大人说话呢
Not now, Mace. Lord Tywin and I are speaking.
总之  我不知道你在抱怨什么
Anyway, I don't know what you're complaining about.
我也出了钱的
I'm paying my share.
要不要我们给半数肉饼都插上金玫瑰
Shall we stick golden roses in half the meat pies
宣扬你的慷慨大方
to commemorate your generosity?
不必  你诚心感谢一句就够了
No, your heartfelt thank-you is its own reward.
我觉得吧  用不着多久你还要道谢
I would imagine I'd be hearing it again before long.
打仗很烧钱
Wars are rather expensive.
"铁金库不容拖欠"
"The Iron Bank will have its due."
他们可乐意把这话挂在嘴上
How they love to remind everyone.
跟你们兰尼斯特家说有债必还一样
Almost as much as you Lannisters with your debts.
我不担心铁金库
I'm not worried about the Iron Bank.
以你的英明怎会小觑铁金库
We both know you're smarter than that.
来吧  泰温  为年轻人的爱情庆祝吧
Come, Tywin, let us celebrate young love.
都搞定了
All taken care of.
-你看着她上船了  -对  她上船了
- You saw her board the ship? - Aye, she's on it.
你看着船开了
You saw the ship sail away?
除了你我和瓦里斯  没人知道她在船上
No one knows she's there but you, me, and Varys.
你怎么确定
How do you know?
如果有人不请自来地跟踪我
Because if someone follows me without an invitation,
我保证他们再也不能跟踪别人了
I'm the last person they ever follow.
有人跟踪你吗
There's someone following you?
她走了
She's gone.
我知道你不愿意相信  但她走了
I know you don't want to believe it, but she is.
去喝酒吧  喝到感觉这事儿做对了为止
Now, go drink till it feels like you did the right thing.
你好啊
Hello.
-你好  -没说你
- Hello. - Not you.
你真是优雅迷人  孩子
You look exquisite, child.
可惜风吹乱了你的头发
The wind has been at you, though.
我还没机会跟你说
I haven't had the opportunity to tell you
听说你哥哥的事我有多遗憾
how sorry I was to hear about your brother.
战火无情  但在婚礼上杀人
War is war, but killing a man at a wedding,
实在骇人听闻
horrid.
什么样的禽兽干得出这等事
What sort of monster would do such a thing?
好像人们还需要更多理由惧怕婚姻一样
As if men need more reasons to fear marriage.
夫人好  老夫人来了
My lady. My lady.
提利昂大人  你瞧  也没那么惨
Lord Tyrion, you see? Not as bad as all that.
兴许你的穷丈夫
Perhaps if your pauper husband
卖了他的骡子和最后一双鞋
were to sell his mule and his last pair of shoes,
就有钱带你去高庭做客了
he might be able to afford to bring you to Highgarden for a visit.
现在和平已经降临  一切都好了
Now that peace has come and all is right with the world,
四处看看对你有好处
it would do you good to see some of it.
容我失陪  该去吃点
You must excuse me. It's time I ate
我付钱买的食物了
some of this food I paid for.
*红狮子斗黄狮子*
*In a coat of gold or a coat of red*
*爪牙锋利不留情*
*a lion still has claws,*
*出手致命...*
* And mine, my lord... *
很好很好  滚吧
Very good. Very good. Off you go.
亲爱的  我们不如现在宣布吧
My love, why don't we make the announcement?
诸位
Everyone.
王后有话要说
The queen would like to say a few words.
我们如此幸运
We are so fortunate
能享受这精致的饮食
to enjoy this marvelous food and drink.
但不是所有人都如此幸运
Not all among us are so lucky.
感谢诸神  给刚刚结束的战争带来公正结局
To thank the gods for bringing the recent war to a just end,
乔佛里国王决定
King Joffrey has decreed
我们宴会所剩的食物
that the leftovers from our feast
将送给城里最穷的人
be given to the poorest in his city.
你是我们的榜样
You're an example to us all.
詹姆爵士  非常抱歉
Ser Jaime, I'm very sorry.
洛拉斯爵士  没关系
Ser Loras, it's quite all right.
您妹妹非常漂亮
Your sister looks very beautiful.
您姐姐也是
As does yours.
期待你的婚礼吗
So, looking forward to your wedding?
非常期待
Yes, very much.
您父亲和家父都非常看好联姻的前景
Our fathers are both rather keen on the prospect.
确实如此
They certainly are.
或许该他俩结婚才对
Perhaps they should get married.
如果你真娶了瑟曦  她会趁你睡着杀死你
If you were to marry Cersei, she'd murder you in your sleep.
如果你真在死掉前让她怀了孩子
If you somehow managed to put a child in her first,
她会连孩子也杀
she'd murder him, too,
都不用等他呱呱坠地
long before he drew his first breath.
你很幸运  这些事都不会发生
Luckily for you, none of this will happen
因为你永远娶不到她
because you'll never marry her.
你也娶不到
And neither will you.
陛下  国王陛下  王后陛下
Your Grace. My king. My queen.
布蕾妮小姐
Lady Brienne.
你能来真好
So good of you to come.
我不是什么小姐  王后陛下
I'm no lady, Your Grace.
你刚才鞠躬了
Did you just bow?
抱歉  太后陛下
Apologies, Your Grace.
我不大会行屈膝礼
I never did master the curtsy.
就是你杀了蓝礼·拜拉席恩
You're the one who put a sword through Renly Baratheon.
不是  亲爱的  布蕾妮跟那事没关系
That's not true, my love. Brienne had nothing to do with it.
真可惜
A shame.
我还打算给杀了那叛徒的人封爵呢
I'd knight the man that put an end to that deviant's life.
我只想祝贺你们  愿你们好运
I just wanted to congratulate you both and wish you good fortune.
国家已经打了太久的仗
The country has been at war too long.
愿您的江山长治久安
I hope your reign is long and peaceful.
-好好好  -谢谢你
- Yes, yes. - Thank you.
希望我们以后常见面
I hope we see more of you.
布蕾妮小姐
Lady Brienne.
你是塞尔温·塔斯伯爵的女儿
You're Lord Selwyn Tarth's daughter.
不管愿不愿意  你都是贵族小姐
That makes you a lady whether you want to be or not.
您说得是  太后陛下
As you say, your Grace.
谢谢你
I owe you my gratitude.
把我弟弟平安带回君临
You returned my brother safely to King's Landing.
其实是他救了我  太后陛下
In truth, he rescued me, Your Grace.
还不止一次
More than once.
是吗
Did he?
这我倒没听说过
Haven't heard that story before.
恐怕算不上什么精彩的故事
Not such a fascinating story, I'm afraid.
你倒是有不少精彩的故事
I'm sure you have many fascinating stories.
宣誓效忠蓝礼·拜拉席恩
Sworn to Renly Baratheon.
宣誓效忠凯特琳·史塔克
Sworn to Catelyn Stark.
现在又轮到我弟弟了
And now my brother.
三天两头地改换门庭
Must be exciting to flit from one camp to the next
看上谁就效忠谁  一定很刺激吧
serving whichever lord or lady you fancy.
我并没有效忠您的弟弟  太后陛下
I don't serve your brother, your Grace.
可你爱上他了
But you love him.
告退  太后陛下
Your Grace.
不行不行  你还是来我房间让我亲自检查
No, no, come to my chambers and I will examine you personally.
-她不会去的  -太后陛下
- She'll do no such thing. - Oh, Your Grace.
是这位小姐向我咨询...
Yes, well, this young lady sought my advice...
你该去找科本  他很厉害
You should see Qyburn. He's quite good.
-是  太后陛下  -科本  那倒霉家伙
- Your Grace. - Qyburn? Deplorable man.
他那些恶心的实验真是让学城蒙羞
Brought shame on the Citadel with his repugnant experiments.
比你用那双老手摸姑娘大腿还恶心吗
More repugnant than your gnarled fingers on that girl's thighs?
太后陛下  我是堂堂正正的学士
Your Grace, I am a man of learning.
你惹恼了我的小弟弟
My little brother had you sent to the Black Cells
结果被他扔进黑牢
when you annoyed him.
你觉得要是惹恼了我  会有什么下场
What do you think I could do to you if you annoyed me?
我向来无意惹恼任何人
I never meant to annoy anyone.
可事实如此  你现在就惹恼我了
But you are. You annoy me right now.
你在我面前的每一次呼吸都惹恼了我
Every breath you draw in my presence annoys me.
你给我听好了
So here's what I want you to do.
马上给我滚
I want you to leave my presence.
滚出婚宴现场
Leave this wedding right now.
去厨房通知下人
Go to the kitchens and instruct them
婚宴的剩饭
that all the leftovers from the feast
全部拿到狗舍去
will be brought to the kennels.
太后陛下  玛格丽王后...
Your Grace, Queen Margaery--
太后现在命令你
The queen is telling you
把剩饭都拿去喂狗
the leftovers will feed the dogs
不然就拿你喂狗
or you will.
谁把我家弄臣的帽子打下来  赏一枚金龙
A gold dragon to whoever knocks my fool's hat off.
你心情不错
You're in rather a good mood.
-是的  -我就不问原因了
- I suppose I am. - I won't ask why.
-小乐子而已  -太后陛下  泰温大人
- Small pleasures. - Your Grace. Lord Tywin.
奥柏伦亲王
Prince Oberyn.
你们一定还没见过艾拉莉亚
I don't believe you have met Ellaria.
这位是首相泰温·兰尼斯特大人
This is the Lord Hand Tywin Lannister
以及摄政太后瑟曦·兰尼斯特
and Cersei Lannister the Queen Regent.
现在是前摄政太后了
I suppose it is former Queen Regent now.
首相大人  瑟曦夫人
Lord Hand and Lady Cersei,
这是艾拉莉亚·沙德
Ellaria Sand.
见过大人  夫人
My lord. My lady.
幸会
Charmed.
我还是头一回见到姓沙德的
Can't say I've ever met a Sand before.
多恩那里到处都是
We are everywhere in Dorne.
我的兄弟姐妹数以万计
I have 10,000 brothers and sisters.
私生子女是激情的结晶  不是吗
Bastards are born of passion, aren't they?
我们多恩人从不鄙薄他们
We don't despise them in Dorne.
是吗  你们肚量真大
No? How tolerant of you.
我想这是种解脱  瑟曦夫人
I expect it is a relief, Lady Cersei,
卸下您的王权重担
giving up your regal responsibilities.
戴了这么多年王冠
Wearing the crown for so many years
您的脖子免不了弯曲变形吧
must have left your neck a bit crooked.
恐怕你永远都不会知道了  奥柏伦亲王
I suppose you'll never know, Prince Oberyn.
你哥哥不能来参加婚礼真是遗憾
It's a shame your older brother couldn't attend the wedding.
请代我们向他致意
Please give him our regards.
幸运的话  痛风症状会逐渐减轻
With any luck, the gout will abate with time
这样他就又能走路了
and he will be able to walk again.
据说这是富贵病
They call it the rich man's disease.
您没有患上真是奇迹
A wonder you don't have it.
我们这边的富人
Noblemen in my part of the country
欣赏不来多恩富人的生活方式
don't enjoy the same lifestyle as our counterparts in Dorne.
百里不同风  千里不同俗
People everywhere have their differences.
有些地方门第观念极重
In some places the highborn frown upon those of low birth.
而有些地方将奸杀妇孺
In other places the rape and murder of women and children
视作极其低劣的行为
is considered distasteful.
至于您  前摄政太后  应该深感庆幸
What a fortunate thing for you, former Queen Regent,
您的女儿弥赛菈被送去的
that your daughter Myrcella has been sent
是后一种地方
to live in the latter sort of place.
全都闭嘴  空出地来
Everyone, silence! Clear the floor.
今天的娱乐消遣已经够多了
There's been too much amusement here today.
但王室婚礼可不是什么娱乐消遣
A royal wedding is not an amusement.
王室婚礼即是历史
A royal wedding is history.
我们所有人都该停下来审视我们的历史
The time has come for all of us to contemplate our history.
诸位大人
My lords...
夫人
my ladies...
有请
I give you
乔佛里国王
King Joffrey...
蓝礼  史坦尼斯
...Renly, Stannis,
罗柏·史塔克  巴隆·葛雷乔伊
Robb Stark, Balon Greyjoy.
五王之战
The War of the Five Kings.
我是合法的国王
I'm the Rightful King.
-北境之王  -来吧
- King in the North! - Yes!
叛徒  你是叛徒
Traitor. You're a traitor.
以七国之名
For the Seven Kingdoms!
开战
Let the war begin.
蓝礼  你才不是什么国王
Renly, you're no king.
滚开  伤风败俗的家伙  滚
Away, degenerate. Away. Away.
当心点
Ooh, careful.
-继续  -我要你成为我的王子
- Go on. - I want you to be my prince.
史坦尼斯
Stannis!
谁拿到金子了  史塔克
Who's got the gold now, Stark?
我是合法的国王  来挑战我啊  恶棍们
I am the rightful king. Challenge me, ruffian.
-接招  -我要淹死了  要淹死了
- Take that. - I'm drowning. I'm drowning.
我是北境之王
I am the King in the North!
别放野火
Not wildfire!
结束后打赏他们每人二十金龙
Pay each of them 20 gold when this is done.
是  大人
Yes, my lord.
我们再想别的法子感谢国王
We'll have to find another way to thank the king.
冲啊
Charge!
准备  再来
Ready, again.
我是北境之王
I am the King in the North!
-冲啊  -冲啊
- Charge! - Charge!
好啊
Yes!
你的头
Your head!
先生们  献丑了
Fine gentlemen.
打得漂亮  打得漂亮
Well fought. Well fought.
拿去  冠军的奖赏
Here you are. Champion's purse.
不过你还不是冠军  对吧
Though you're not the champion yet, are you?
真正的冠军要打败所有挑战者
A true champion defeats all the challengers.
肯定还有人胆敢
Surely there are others out there
挑战我的权威
who still dare to challenge my reign.
舅舅
Uncle.
不然你来  他们肯定还有多余的戏服
How about you? I'm sure they have a spare costume.
上一次战场对我而言已足矣  陛下
One taste of combat was enough for me, Your Grace.
我还想保住剩下的脸呢
I would like to keep what remains of my face.
您应当上阵才是
I think you should fight him.
他们的表演不过是
This was but a poor imitation
对您在战场上英勇表现的拙劣模仿
of your own bravery on the field of battle.
我可是亲眼见识过的
I speak as a firsthand witness.
拿好新铸的瓦雷利亚钢剑  爬下您那高桌子
Climb down from the high table with your new Valyrian sword
让大家见识真正的国王如何赢得王座
and show everyone how a true king wins his throne.
不过当心点
Be careful, though.
这家伙显然饥渴得昏了头
This one is clearly mad with lust.
要是国王还没等到洞房花烛夜
It would be a tragedy for the king to lose his virtue
就失了身  那就惨咯
hours before his wedding night.
多好的酒
A fine vintage.
洒了真可惜
Shame that it spilled.
不是洒出来的
It did not spill.
爱人  回到我身边
My love, come back to me.
该我父亲祝酒了
It's time for my father's toast.
酒杯空空  我如何接受祝酒呢
Well, how does he expect me to toast without wine?
舅舅  你来当我的侍酒
Uncle, you can be my cupbearer
既然你没胆量上场比武
seeing as you're too cowardly to fight.
如此殊荣  实不敢当
Your Grace does me a great honor.
这不是什么殊荣
It's not meant as an honor.
捡回来
Bring me my goblet.
空杯子可不成
What good is an empty cup?
倒酒
Fill it.
跪下
Kneel.
在你国王面前跪下
Kneel before your king.
跪下
Kneel.
我说了
I said...
跪下
kneel!
看哪  馅饼来了
Look, the pie.
王后  瞧着
My queen.
精彩
Wonderful.
我的英雄
My hero.
-我们可以离席吗  -试试看
- Can we leave now? - Let's find out.
舅舅
Uncle.
上哪儿去啊
Where are you going?
你是我的侍酒  忘了吗
You're my cupbearer, remember?
我去换下这身湿衣服  陛下
I thought I might change out of these wet clothes, Your Grace.
不用  不用  你这样子最好看了
No, no, no. No, you're perfect the way you are.
给我倒酒
Serve me my wine.
快点  馅饼太干了
Well, hurry up. This pie is dry.
很好
Mm, good.
要喝点酒冲下去
Needs washing down.
恕我失陪  陛下  珊莎夫人累了
If it please Your Grace, Lady Sansa is very tired.
不行
No.
不行  你们不准走
No, you'll wait here...
陛下
Your Grace?
没事
It's nothing.
-他噎住了  -快帮帮这可怜的孩子
- He's choking! - Help the poor boy.
-白痴  快帮帮你们的国王  -躲开
- Idiots, help your king. - Move away!
-乔佛里  乔佛里  -快救他
- Joffrey! Joffrey! - Help him!
-来人救救他  -乔佛里
- Someone help him! - Joffrey!
-快跟我走  -乔佛里  乔佛里
- Come with me now. - Joffrey! Joffrey!
您想走的话  现在就得走
If you want to live, we have to leave.
别碰他
Don't touch him!
乔佛里
Joffrey.
撑住  乔佛里
Please, Joffrey.
乔佛里  你怎么了
Joffrey, what is it?
救救他
Help him!
我的儿子
My son.
他死了  国王驾崩了
He's gone. Our king is gone.
是他干的
He did this.
他毒死了我儿子
He poisoned my son,
你们的国王
your king.
抓住他  抓住他
Take him. Take him!
抓住他
Take him!
《卡斯特梅的雨季》
*红狮子斗黄狮子*
*In a coat of gold or a coat of red*
*爪牙锋利不留情*
*a lion still has claws,*
*出手致命招招狠*
*And mine are long and sharp, My Lord,*
*汝子莫忘记  汝子莫忘记*
*as long and sharp as yours.*
*噢  他这样说  他这样说*
*And so he spoke, and so he spoke,*
*卡斯特梅的爵爷他这样说*
*that lord of Castamere,*
*然而今天  每逢雨季*
*But now the rains weep o’er his hall,*
*雨水在大厅哭泣  内里却无人影*
*with no one there to hear.*
*然而今天  每逢雨季*
*Yes, now the rains weep o'er his hall,*
*雨水在大厅哭泣  内里却无魂灵*
*and not a soul to hear.*